[Community Wishlist

Search for new games to share.](https://www.steamgifts.com/giveaways/wishlist)

[Learn More

Find out more information.](https://www.steamgifts.com/discussion/9jPml/)

[Guidelines

Community rules and guidelines.](https://www.steamgifts.com/about/guidelines)[FAQ

Frequently asked questions.](https://www.steamgifts.com/about/faq)[Comment Formatting

Syntax for writing comments.](https://www.steamgifts.com/about/comment-formatting)

Help

Other

Legal

This privacy policy outlines how information collected through our service is both used and protected. Information that is requested from users and/or made available to us will be used in accordance with this policy.

### What kinds of information are we collecting?

1. **Information and content that you share with us**
    * We collect information that you provide when using our service. When registering, you will be asked to provide a username, email address and region. Additionally, there are other forms of information that you may choose to share with our community, such as giveaways, discussions, comments, and polls.
2. **Usage information**
    * At times, we may collect or log data on how you are using our service, such as pages you are visiting, actions you are performing, the date you registered, and when you were last online.
3. **Steam information**
    * When using the option to sign in through Steam, we will collect information corresponding to your Steam account. This information includes your Steam ID, avatar, games, playtime, wishlist, and groups.
4. **Patreon information**
    * If you link your Patreon account, we will collect information regarding your pledges to our service and information about your Patreon account, such as your Patreon ID and avatar.
5. **Device information**
    * We may also collect attributes related to your device as you use our service, such as the IP address, unique identifiers, device IDs, cookies, operating system, and browser.
6. **Communication**
    * You may also provide information when communicating with us. Such forms of communication may include direct emails or support tickets.

### How will we use this information?

1. **To provide and personalize our service**
    
    * We will display your username and avatar throughout our service, and next to content that you choose to share.
    * An overview of your account and activity will be used for your user profile.
    * The region you choose during registration will give you access to the appropriate region restricted giveaways.
    * Information that we collect regarding your Steam account will be used to help personalize our service. For example, you have the option to only display giveaways corresponding to games on your Steam wishlist, or the option to view giveaways which are exclusively available to your Steam groups. Playtime data will be used to help recommend giveaways that might be of interest to you, and other users.
    * We may also use your information to administrate our service, and during communications with our staff to help resolve support tickets.
    * If you link your Patreon account, we will use your pledge information to apply the appropriate rewards to your account.
2. **Safety and integrity**
    
    * We analyze Steam, usage, and device information to ensure the integrity and security of our service, and to prevent users from registering more than one account.
    * We will use your Steam information to provide appropriate restrictions when necessary. This data helps to ensure that you do not enter to win games which you already own on Steam. It also allows you to only enter downloadable content (DLC) giveaways when you own the appropriate base game. If giveaways are only available to particular Steam groups, we use your Steam information to know whether or not you have access to view those giveaways.
    * We temporarily store server logs about user activity to help us identify abuse.
3. **Communication**
    
    * We may use your information as a means of communicating with you regarding our service, or to contact you if you choose to opt in to marketing related email notifications.
    * The email address you provide will be used for service notifications, to inform you when you need to send a gift, or when you have won a giveaway. It will also be used to facilitate communication between giveaway creators and giveaway winners.
4. **Aggregate information**
    
    * At times we will aggregate non-personal information, such as demographics or usage statistics.
5. **Analytics**
    
    * User activity and device information is used to assess how our business is performing, and to provide insights into how we can improve our service.
    * We also use information about your activity to generate statistics for you, such as your probability of winning per day, your contributions over time, or how your Steam account compares to other users.
6. **Advertising**
    
    * Usage and device information is used to help show personalized advertising, or relevant sponsored content.

### How is this information shared?

1. **Account information**
    
    * We will share your username and avatar publicly to identify you within our community.
    * An overview of your account which includes the date you registered, when you were last online, and a summary of your activity will also be publicly available.
    * When you win a giveaway, your email address will be shared with the corresponding giveaway creator so that they are able to deliver their gift, and communicate with you.
2. **Information you provide**
    
    * If you choose to share giveaways, discussions, comments, or polls with our community, they will be publicly available. Possible restrictions may be applied, such as limiting a giveaway to a particular Steam group.
    * If you attach keys to your giveaways, those keys will be shared with the winners of your giveaways.
3. **Administration**
    
    * Our staff will be able to access your information to help administrate our service, identify abuse, or resolve support tickets.
4. **Aggregate Information**
    
    * We may share non-personal aggregate information with our community, advertisers and/or other organizations. For example, we might inform an advertiser how many unique users visit our site per day.
5. **Analytics**
    
    * We use Google Analytics with anonymized IP addresses to help understand how users engage with our service. To learn more about the data Google collects and processes, please visit [http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). To opt out of Google Analytics, you can install the browser add-on provided by Google, [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).
6. **Advertising**
    
    * We use third party advertising companies to serve ads when you are using our service. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide relevant advertisements about goods and services that may interest you. If you would like more information about this practice, or wish to opt out, refer to the consumer website of the NAI by visiting [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/), or the DAA by visiting [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/).
7. **Law enforcement or legal requests**
    
    * We reserve the right to share personal information with law enforcement, or to respond to legal requests when we believe doing so is necessary to prevent fraud or abuse, to protect our legal rights, and/or the safety of our users or others.

### Third party links or services

* We may include third party links or services. These third parties have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these links or services.

### Data retention

* We will store information for as long as required to provide our service to you, or to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected as described in this policy. We also take into account legal or regulatory requirements when determining how long data needs to be retained. Certain information may be retained for as long as necessary to secure our service, conduct audits, or resolve disputes.
    
* We save encrypted backups of our database on a regular basis, and we keep those backups for a period of one year.

### What is our legal basis for processing your personal information?

1. When it is required to provide our product or service, or to fulfill our commitments to you under our terms of service.
2. When you have given us consent, such as opting in to marketing emails.
3. When necessary to protect your vital interests, or those of another person.
4. When necessary to comply with legal obligations.
5. When necessary in the public interest.
6. When we have a legitimate interest in using your information, unless those interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms that require protection of personal data. For example, to provide and personalize our service, to secure our service, to administrate our service, to communicate with you, to understand how users are engaging with our service, and to improve the effectiveness of our advertising.

### What are your rights under data protection laws?

Residents from specific regions, such as the EU, are provided certain rights regarding their personal information. These rights are listed below and are subject to applicable law.

* The right to be informed about how your personal information is being collected and processed.
* The right to access your personal information.
* The right to correct inaccurate personal information, or to have it completed if it is incomplete.
* The right to be forgotten, and to have your personal information erased.
* The right to restrict or suppress the processing of your personal information.
* The right to data portability, allowing you to obtain and reuse your personal information for your own purposes, or for other services.
* The right to object to the processing of your personal information.
* Rights related to automated decision making and processing, such as profiling.

### How can you delete your account and personal information?

You will need to sign into your SteamGifts account and then navigate to the [delete account](https://www.steamgifts.com/account/privacy/delete-account) page. Once you click the button to proceed with the deletion at the bottom of that page, your account and personal information will automatically be erased in two weeks.

### Changes to our privacy policy

We may change this privacy policy from time to time by updating this page in order to reflect changes in the law and/or our practices. We encourage you to check this privacy policy for changes whenever you visit our website.

### Contact

The data controller responsible for your information is SteamGifts, which you can contact by [email](mailto:privacy@steamgifts.com).

Last modified 6 years ago by [cg](https://www.steamgifts.com/user/cg).

SteamGifts

Browse

Help

Legal

Powered by
